( MAN COUGHING )
( CHICKEN CLUCKING )
( SOLDIERS YELLING )
MAN ON RADIO : Charlie-Fox , Charlie-Fox 6 ,
Roger , be advised ...
We 'll have resupplies down by chopper . Over .
Strong shit , man .
( STATIC CRACKLING )
Where the fuck are the goddamn gooks already ?
I don 't think them fucking dinks are even out there .
Jesus , this shit 's something else .
Hey , Professor , how many times can you shit in an hour ?
( CHUCKLES )
Professor got beaucoup-shits , man .
Why do you even bother pulling them up ?
( CHUCKLES )
You jerking off again , huh , Jake ?
( LAUGHS )
Come over here and jerk on this . Come choke my black rooster .
( ALL LAUGHING )
Please ?
He 's asking politely .
Ain 't got a fucking tweezer , man .
ALL : Whoa !
( ALL LAUGHING )
Shit ! We got movement in the tree line .
- Shit ! - Movement in the tree line !
( ALL CLAMORING )
( EXPLOSION )
One , three , two , zero !
- Fuck , something 's wrong . - What the fuck 's wrong with you ?
Fuck !
( SCREAMING )
It 's my head . It 's my head .
Help me ! Somebody help me !
Get up ! Get up !
- SOLDIER : Paul , help me , man ! - Get up !
( CHOKING )
Help ! Help me !
What the fuck is wrong with you ? Come on , get up !
Medic ! Medic !
- ( SCREAMING ) - JACOB : Stop it !
You 're crazy , man .
( INDISTINCT SHOUTING )
( BOMB DROPPING )
Medic !
( GUNS FIRING )
( MAN SPLUTTERING )
SOLDIER : Move it ! Move it !
( GROANS )
One , two , three , zero !
- On the floor ! - Fire !
( RETCHING )
( GROANING )
( SCREAMING ) My arm ! My arm ! My arm !
( SCREAMING )
Oh , God ! Fucking shit !
( GROANING )
( SOLDIER SCREAMING )
( GRUNTS )
( HELICOPTER HOVERING )
( EXPLOSION )
( GUN FIRING )
( GASPS )
( GROANS )
( SIGHS )
Excuse me .
Do you know if we 've passed Bergen Street yet ?
Bergen ?
Um ... I fell asleep .
All right . Okay .
( WHEELS SCREECHING )
( DOOR OPENING )
Fuck .
( SIGHS )
( WATER DRIPPING )
( SQUEAKING )
Shit .
( CLINKING )
( WIND BLOWING )
( DOG BARKING )
( BABY CRYING )
( DOG PANTING )
Hey , Chester .
Go back to sleep .
Get insomnia again ?
JEZZIE : Jake , is that you ?
( GLASS SHATTERING )
What the hell did you do ? Move all the furniture ?
I just moved the chair , that 's all .
That help ?
( SIGHS ) Yeah , thanks .
So , what do you think ?
About what ?
The room .
- Oh , ask me tomorrow . - It is tomorrow .
How come you 're so late ?
Bud Nash didn 't show up again .
Called in sick . He 's always sick .
So , I worked .
Got some overtime .
What happened to your pants ?
Oh , don 't ask .
You look terrible .
Thanks .
( BOTH CHUCKLING )
JEZZIE : Mmm .
( GASPING )
( MEN CHATTERING IN DISTANCE )
( SOFTLY ) Help me . Help me .
( GASPING )
Oh , fuck .
( SIGHS )
You 're up ?
Oh , fuck .
( EXHALES )
What 's that ?
Your kid dropped it off .
- Who , Jed ? - No , the little one .
Eli . ( CHUCKLES )
Why can 't you remember their names ?
They 're weird names .
They 're biblical names .
They were prophets .
Well , personally , I never went for church names .
( JACOB LAUGHING )
What ?
Where do you think Jezebel came from ?
Nobody calls me that .
( LAUGHS )
You 're such a heathen , Jezzie .
How 'd I ever get involved with such a fucking ninny ?
You sold your soul , remember ? That 's what you told me .
- Oh , yeah ? For what ? - A good lay .
Look what I got ...
BOTH : The best .
( BOTH LAUGHING )
( GRUNTING )
So , what 's in the bag ?
- Pictures . - Oh , yeah ?
Your wife was gonna toss them ,
so , what 's-his-name dropped it over on the way to school .
Eli . Eli . E-Ii .
Well ...
( LAUGHING ) These are great .
MV Drom .
Yeah ? Look at this baby .
Aw , who 's that ?
- Isn 't that the cutest baby you 've ever seen ? - Little fat little thing .
- That 's me . - That 's you ? Let me see .
No , that 's all right . This fat little thing . You don 't have to look .
You don 't have to look .
Who 's this ?
JACOB : Sarah .
Sarah .
I can see what you mean .
What ?
Why you left .
What do you mean ?
Jake , she looks like a real bitch .
( LAUGHS )
Well , she looked good then .
Not to me .
You didn 't marry her .
Hello , baby .
How you doing ?
( INAUDIBLE )
( CRYING )
What 's wrong ?
Is this the one who died before you went to Vietnam ?
Yeah , it 's Gabe .
Oh , God .
Sorry .
Took me by surprise . I didn 't expect to see him today .
What are you doing ? Stop it !
( JEZZIE SIGHS )
I don 't like things that make you cry .
( DOOR CLOSES )
I didn 't cry .
( SINGING SONNYBOY )
( HONKING )
( CONTINUES SINGING )
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
( JACOB HUMMING )
Hey !
In to get your check ? You one greedy motherfucker , man .
- Don 't you know that ? - ( LAUGHING )
( BOTH CHUCKLING )
Hi .
- How 's it going ? - Better now .
- Yeah ? - Mmm-hmm .
- I 'm going to go home . - What 's wrong ?
Oh , just one of those days .
My back 's killing me . I 'm gonna see Louis .
Oh , no , not again . Your boss is going to kill you .
Well , what can you do ?
Well , I 'll miss riding home with you .
- Yeah ? - I was looking fen / vard to it .
- Yeah ? Easy . My back . - ( MOANING )
( GROANING )
Come on , Jake , that didn 't hurt .
How do you know ?
( CHUCKLES ) I know you . How come you 're so tense today ?
I don 't know . What can I tell you , Louis ?
I saw Sarah the other day .
- Oh , yeah ? - Mmm-hmm .
Her knee acting up ?
A bit .
So , what did she have to say ?
Turn on your right side .
How about the other right ?
I don 't understand you philosophers .
You got the world figured out ,
but you can 't remember the difference between right and left .
- So , what did she say ? - Oh , not much .
She 's like you that way , two clams . No wonder your marriage didn 't last .
Put your hand on your hip .
Take a deep breath .
( INHALING )
And let it out slowly ...
- ( EXHALING ) - ... slowly , slowly .
( BONES CRACKING )
That 's good .
Now , turn to your left .
Did she talk about the boys ?
She says you 're a son of a bitch , and she regrets the day she set eyes on you .
( LAUGHING )
I thought she didn 't say much .
She didn 't . That 's about all she said . Put your hand on your hip .
Take a breath .
Easy .
( BONES CRACKING )
On your back .
I think she still loves you .
I don 't think so .
She doesn 't stop talking about you .
That 's love , Jake .
I think you should go back to her .
She threw me out , remember ?
The problem is you spent six years getting a PhD
and then went to work for the post office .
( LAUGHING )
Well , what can I tell you ?
After Nam , I didn 't want to think anymore .
Any other brain but yours , I 'd agree .
Now , relax .
Now , relax . This is going to be a little strong .
That a boy . That a boy .
MAN : I found one .
I think he 's still alive .
( CHUCKLES )
What did you ... What did you do to me ?
I had to get in there .
It 's a deep adjustment .
Rest a moment . Let it set a bit .
I had a weird flash just now .
What ?
I don 't know . I 've been having them recently .
You know , you look like an angel , Louis .
Like an overgrown cherub .
( LAUGHING )
Anyone ever tell you that ?
Yeah .
You .
Every time I see you .
You 're a lifesaver , Louis .
I know .
( MEN CHATTERING )
BOY : Mr. Postman .
ALL : Mr. Postman .
Where 's your letters , baby ?
- Hey , Mr. Postman . - ( ALL SHOUTING )
GIRL : Where 's your bag ?
BOY : Shake your thing .
You know , we should say at him . Wait !
( SINGING PLEASE MR. POSTMAN )
- Where you going ? Where you going ? - Come back !
We don 't remember the words . I 'm sorry .
( TIRES SCREECHING )
Look out ! Look out !
Singer ?
Please , Elizabeth , sit down .
Hi , I need to see Dr. Carlson , please .
Carlson ? Is he new here ?
New ? No , he 's been here for years .
Not according to my charts .
Do you have an appointment ?
No . Listen , I need to see him . I know where his room is .
Just give me a pass . I won 't be long , 10 minutes .
Our doctors are seen by appointment only .
Damn .
I was in the veterans ' outpatient program . He knows me .
What was your name ?
Singer . Jacob Singer .
( SOFTLY ) I 've got a lot of work here . Haven 't even had my lunch yet .
( NURSE MUMBLING )
I 'm sorry , but there 's no record of a Jacob Singer in our files .
What do you mean " no record " ?
Do I have to spell it out for you ? There is nothing there .
That 's ridiculous . I 've been coming here for years .
Listen to me . I 'm ... I 'm ...
I ... I need to see Dr. Carlson .
If it is an emergency , we have a staff of psychiatric social workers .
There 's about an hour 's wait .
Would you just fill out this form , please ?
I won 't see any social worker .
( GLASS SHATTERING )
I want to talk to Dr. Carlson . He knows me .
( GASPS )
Hey ! Come back here !
Hey ! Hey , come back here !
Hey !
Look out ! Look out ! Get off ! Whoa ! Whoa !
- Hey , come on ! - PATIENT 1 : Hold him .
PATIENT 2 : He made it , he made it .
Can I help you ?
Where 's Dr. Carlson ? Isn 't this his office ?
Bejust a minute .
Why don 't we step out in the hall ?
It 's okay .
I 'm so sorry . Dr. Carlson died .
Died ?
It was a car accident .
Oh , Jesus .
When ?
About a month ago . Just before Thanksgiving .
How 'd it happen ?
No one really knows . They say it blew up .
Blew up ?
What do you mean , blew up ?
I really don 't know .
Is there anything I can do for you ?
Do you ... Do you want me to get you someone ?
No . I 'm okay .
JEZZIE : Maybe it 's the pressure , Jake .
You know , the money . Things like that .
Or your wife .
Why do you bring her up ?
She 's always on your mind .
I never talk about her .
It has nothing to do with talking .
Maybe it 's the war .
You can 't spend two years in Vietnam and expect ...
Oh , Jezzie , come on .
How does that explain barricaded subway stations ?
How does it explain these fucking creatures ?
Creatu res ?
Jake , New York is filled with creatures , and lots of stations are closed .
They 're like demons , Jezz .
Demons ?
Jake , honey , they 're winos and bag ladies .
Lowlife . That 's all they are . The streets are crawling with them .
( WHISPERING ) Don 't make ' em into something they 're not , hmm ?
These guys were trying to kill me . They were aiming straight at me .
( CHUCKLES ) Kids on a joy ride . It happens all the time .
( SIGHS )
They were inhuman .
( SNICKERS ) Oh , come on .
What were they , Jake ?
You still love me ?
What ?
Do you love me ?
Yeah .
( LADY MARMALADE PLAYING )
Hey , where are you going ? Come with me . Come on .
Do you have a girlfriend ? Do you like her an awful lot ?
Do you want a new girlfriend ?
Because , you know what , I live very close to here ,
and I 'm very lonely .
( LAUGHING )
{ SCREECHES ) { GASPS )
Hey .
Let me look at your hand .
No , thanks .
Go ahead , Jake . Let her do it . She 's real good .
Come on .
Ifsfun .
You left-handed or right-handed ?
Um , right .
- Give it to me . - Okay .
Hmm ? Mmm-hmm . Married man .
( CLICKING TONGUE ) Please .
( CHUCKLES )
Oh , no .
Oh , divorce .
( BOTH LAUGHING )
I like that .
- You see this here , that split ? - Where ?
Right here .
It 's a paper cut .
( LAUGHS ) 0oh , and a sense of humor , too .
( JACOB LAUGHING )
I love it .
Let 's see .
Hey , Jake . Jake .
Come on , baby . Come on and dance with me , just one , huh ?
What , are you flirting ?
Hi .
( CHUCKLES )
Let 's see , this is your heart line ,
and your head line .
Huh ?
( LAUGHING )
And your life line .
You have a very strange line , hon .
( BOTH LAUGHING )
No , it 's not funny .
See , according to this , you 're already dead .
- You 're out of here , baby . - Oh , no , what can you do ?
Just give me your blue eyes before you go , okay ?
( MY THANG PLAYING )
( PEOPLE WHOOPING )
Wait , wait . Jake , come here . Come on . Come on , come on , you can dance .
- Yeah . Shake it . - I don 't want to .
Come on , baby , shake it .
Come on , man , move those legs , brother . Move them size thirteens .
Those are some big fucking feet . Shit .
( INAUDIBLE )
( LAUGHING )
( GRUNTING )
( MOANS )
( SCREAMING )
( CONTINUES SCREAMING )
Jesus , look at that . His guts are hanging out .
You 'll have to push them back in .
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
I have never ... I have never been so mortified in my whole life .
Screaming like that .
I don 't understand what 's gotten into you , Jake .
You 're not acting normal .
I 've been with too many crazies in my life . I don 't want it anymore .
I 'm tired of men flipping out on me .
If you go crazy , Jake , you 're going crazy by yourself , you understand ?
What 's it say ?
Oh , my God . I 'm calling the doctor .
It 's gone to the top .
Great .
Dr. Forrest , I 'm so sorry to bother you .
This is Jezzie Pipkin up on 14-G .
I just took Jake 's temperature , and it says 106 . Could that be right ?
( CHUCKUNG )
Oh , my God .
Get out of bed .
I can 't . I 'm freezing .
Jake , for Pete 's sake , get out of bed !
What did the doctor say ?
That you 'd die on the way to the hospital . Now , come on .
Come on , up , up .
Hold on , hold on . You 're going to be okay , Jake .
What are you doing ?
- Get in there . I got to get more ice . - I 'm freezing !
( RINGING DOORBELL )
( POUNDING ON DOOR )
What 's happening ?
I need some ice right away . He 's running a 106 fever .
- It 's an emergency . Ice . - What ?
Thank you .
Come on , Sam .
Oh , my God . Oh , Jake , 0h , Jake , don 't you die on me . Come on .
Sam , help me ! Sam !
- I 'll help . - JEZZIE : Come on .
- Be careful with him . - Hold on .
Come on . It 's for your own good .
JEZZIE : Come on , Jake . Come on , get him in there .
( EXCLAIMS )
( INDISTINCT )
( SCREAMING )
Hold him ! Hold him ! It 's going to be okay .
It 's going to be okay .
Is he all right ?
He doesn 't like this .
Help me !
- ( JACOB SCREAMING ) - ( SHUSHING )
Stop iu .
Don 't you die on me , Jake .
Stop it ! You 're killing me !
Shit .
What was that ?
I 'm freezing .
I 'm not cold .
Of course you 're not cold . You have all the covers .
Must be 10 degrees in here .
( SIGHS )
I 'm telling you , Sarah ,
if you want fresh air , you can sleep on the fire escape .
From now on , that window 's closed .
It 's not healthy when it 's closed .
Healthy ? You call this healthy ?
I 'm going to die of pneumonia . This is healthy ?
What a dream I was having .
I was living with another woman .
You know who it was ?
I don 't want to know .
Jezebel from the post office .
You remember her . You met her at the Christmas party that time .
I was living with her .
God , what a nightmare .
( SNICKERS )
There were all these demons , and I was on fire .
I was burning from ice .
Guilty thoughts .
See what happens when you cheat on me , even in your mind ?
She was really good in bed .
( CHUCKLES ) Go to sleep .
She had these great thighs .
Oh , I thought you said it was a nightmare .
It was . It was a nightmare .
( BOTH CHUCKLING )
It was a terrible , terrible nightmare .
( LU LLABY TINKLING )
Daddy , what was that noise ?
( CHUCKLES )
What are you doing up ?
( LAUGHING )
It 's cold .
- Well , tell your mother . - Go back to bed , darling .
Will you tuck me in ?
Who , her ?
No , Daddy .
- Shit . - Good night , sweetheart .
Oh , God . Come on .
Good night , darling .
( MUSIC STOPS )
Okay . Close your eyes .
( HUMMING SONNYBOY )
( SINGING ) I don 't mind the gray skies .
You make them ...
Blue ?
( CHUCKLES )
( CONTINUES SINGING ) Sonny Boy .
When I 'm old and gray , dear .
Promise you won 't stray , dear .
I love you so .
Sonny ...
BOV -
- Dad ? - Yeah , Jed ?
You forgot my allowance .
Your allowance ?
It 's 5 : 00 in the morning . We 'll talk about it at breakfast .
All right , but don 't forget .
I love you , Dad .
( CHUCKLES ) What is this , a convention ? I love you too , Pickles . Go back to sleep .
GABE : Wait .
Don 't go .
I 'm not going anywhere .
I 'm right here .
Close your eyes .
See you in the morning .
Don 't shut it .
Open it a bit more .
- There ? - A little bit more .
- There ? - Good .
I love you , Sarah .
( LEAVES RUSTLING )
MAN 1 : Watch the head .
MAN 2 : There 's been a mistake .
Move it !
MAN ON RADIO : We got a fucking chance down here .
Dec / are an emergency . Over .
( HELICOPTER WHIRRING )
You 're a lucky guy , Jake . You must have friends in high places .
( HELICOPTER HOVERING )
MAN : ( ON TV ) Let 's get down to Orson .
I was going to vote for three all the way through ,
and I switched to two with some trepidation , because she said one over one ,
which means number one of an addition of one ,
and I think only an artist would know that .
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING ON TV )
Jake ?
You 're going to be all right , Jake .
Oh , you 're going to be fine .
Am I ...
Am I home ?
Yeah . You 're right here .
Home .
Doctor says you 're lucky your brains didn 't boil .
What a night , Jake , huh ?
You were screaming and kicking .
And you kept saying , " Sarah , close the window , "
over and over .
And talking to your kids , ( CHUCKLES ) even the dead one .
Weird , huh ?
You know you melted 50 pounds of ice in eight hours ?
Am I dead ?
( CRYING ) Oh , no .
No . You 're right here .
Doctor says you got to rest .
You see , he says you have a virus . ( LAUGHS )
That 's what they always say when they don 't know what it is .
Now , you just lie here , okay ?
You know , you really ought to get out today .
You can 't just sit around like this all the time , Jake , it 's not healthy .
It 's not good for your mind .
Go take a walk or something .
Do something . Go to a movie .
Go enjoy yourself .
One of us should be having a good time .
Anybody in there ?
Anybody home ?
Who are you ?
Fuck you .
Two weeks of this shit ! I 've had enough .
Go ahead and rot if you want .
Have a good fucking day .
( PHONE RINGING )
Hello .
- PAUL : Jake ? - Yeah ?
- It 's Paul . Paul Gruniger . - Paul Gruniger .
Paul . Paul Gruniger . Jesus , how are you ? God ! It 's been like five , six years .
- Yeah , A long time . - So , what 's up ?
- Nothing much . - Yeah . Well , same here .
/ need to see you , Jake .
I 'd love to see you , man , but I 've been kind of laid up . I 've been sick .
/ need to see you .
All right .
PAUL : Something 's wrong , Jake .
I don 't know what it is ,
but I can 't talk to anybody about it .
Yet , I figured I could talk to you .
You always used to listen , you know .
I 'm going to hell .
That 's as straight as I can put it .
And don 't tell me that I 'm crazy , 'cause I know I 'm not .
They 're coming after me .
Who is ?
They 've been following me .
They 're coming out of the walls .
I can 't trust anybody .
But I got to talk to somebody .
I got to talk to somebody , or I 'm going to fly out of my fucking mind !
Mind your business .
I don 't know who they are or what they are ,
but they 're going to get me , and I 'm scared , Jake .
I 'm so scared , I can 't do anything .
I can 't go to my sister 's .
I can 't even ...
( CRYING ) I can 't even go home .
I don 't know what to do .
Paul . Shit .
Paul , I know what you 're talking about .
What do you mean ?
I 've seen them , too .
You 've seen them ?
I 've seen them , too . Everywhere , like a plague .
My God , I thought I was the only one .
Yeah , me , too . I thought I was going out of my fucking mind .
I know , I know .
Look , I carry these around everywhere with me ,
but they don 't help .
Nothing helps .
( PAUL SOBBING )
What happened ?
What happened that night ?
( MEN SCREAMING )
- What have they done to us ? - I don 't know .
MAN : Profile .
Great . That 's good , that 's good . Go , give it to him .
( GRUNTING )
My lucky day -
( HELICOPTER WHIRRING )
MAN : ( OVER RADIO ) Be advised , we have heavy gunfire ...
( GUNSHOT )
PILOT : Mayday , mayday , mayday !
( GUNS FIRING )
( PEOPLE CLAMORING )
Five minutes to the sea .
( INDISTINCT )
( PEOPLE CHATTERING )
Oh , no , no , no . You have to be strong for your children .
WOMAN : Listen to what she 's saying .
Did anybody see the police report ? Sounds like a bomb to me .
The paper said it was electrical . It was an accident .
That 's bullshit . Someone 's covering something up .
That was no accident . It was set , man .
Why ? Paul wasn 't hated by anybody in the world .
So , what did he say when you 'll went out ? Did he say anything ?
Well , he was upset . He thought people were following him .
- FRANK : Yeah ? Who ? - He didn 't know .
Demons .
Demons ? What the fuck you talking about , demons ?
He thought he was going to hell .
Why did he say that for ? I mean , what would make him say that ?
I mean , that 's strange .
What else did he say , Jake ?
He was scared . He was seeing things coming out of the woodwork .
" They 're trying to get me , " he said .
Did he say what they looked like ?
Excuse me .
In one end and out the other , huh , George ? Still a fucking spaz .
Hope he can hold his dick better than he can hold his bottle .
( CHUCKLES )
What ?
Something weird is going on here . You know , Paul isn 't the first one who 's died .
- Remember Dr. Carlson over at Bellevue ? - Yeah .
His car blew up , too .
Dr. Carlson is dead ?
Yeah . An explosion just like Paul 's .
( ALL CHATTERING )
- We got six guys here going fucking crazy . - Yeah , well , not me , buddy .
All right , not you , Rod ,
but the rest of us are going out of our fucking minds .
Oh , you think it 's got something to do with that night ?
Think it 's got something to do with something .
I think we have to go see the Army .
Think they 're not telling us something . We have to find out what it is .
Oh , come on , Professor .
What makes you think the Army 's going to give you any answers , huh ?
I mean , you 're going to be butting your head up against a brick wall .
We 'll just have to get ourselves a lawyer .
Yeah , you should find yourself a shrink .
You 're all fucking paranoid . It was bad grass . That 's all it was , man .
I mean , there 's no such things as fucking demons . Come on .
( SIGHS )
Carol , I 'm going to need you with your pad in about 15 minutes .
Well , I 'm sorry , Mr. Singer ,
but you know how many people come to me with the injustices of the world ?
It would break your heart .
Listen , Mr. Geary , this is very important to us .
The Army did something to us , and we 've got to find out what .
Army ? The Army . What is with you guys ?
This is not a walk to the library we 're talking about .
This is the U.S. government , for Christ 's sakes .
This is red tape coming out your ass , you know what I mean ?
Yeah , I know what you mean , that 's why we 're here .
We think you can help us .
( CHORTLES )
What am I , Perry Mason ?
( ICE CRUNCHING )
All right . I 'll look into it .
You think we have a chance ?
I need sworn depositions from all of you .
I need a list of every other member of the platoon or their survivors .
This is great .
Yeah , well , I 'll tell you one thing .
If we do find that the military is implicated in this ,
you all stand to make quite a bit of money .
Not that I can predict anything , but class action suits of this kind
have been awarded fairly generous judgments .
That wouldn 't be so bad , would it , Mr. Singer ?
We 're not in it for the money .
- That 's right , Mr. Geary . - Right .
All right , gentlemen , who wants to go first ?
( INAUDIBLE )
Jake , I put a Hungry-Man in the oven .
- It will be ready at a quarter of . - Okay .
I also made you a tossed salad . It 's in the fridge .
Okay , sweetie .
And I got you some apple juice .
- No , not Red Cheek . - Red Cheek .
Oh , shit .
Don 't drink it all .
All right .
Oh , and your lawyer called .
When ?
- When you were in the shower . - Why didn 't you call me ?
He didn 't give me a chance . He hung up on me .
Look , Jake , don 't be upset , okay ?
He 's not taking your case .
What ? What do you mean ?
He said you didn 't have one .
What 's he talking about ?
I don 't know . He was very rude . He said that your friends backed out .
Oh , I don 't believe this .
Oh , baby , I feel terrible .
I 'd stay , but I 'm so late .
We 'll talk when I get home , okay ?
Yeah , yeah .
- Are you all right ? - Yeah , I 'm fine .
( DIALING )
- You sure ? - Mmm-hmm .
Come here . Give me a kiss .
( CHUCKLES )
- I 'll see you later . - Bye , sweetie .
( DOOR CLOSING )
( RINGING )
Hello ?
Frank , hi . It 's Jake . Listen , I just got a strange call from Geary .
He said the guys backed down . What 's he talking about ?
Uh ...
Yeah , that 's right , Jake , we did .
Why ?
I don 't know . It 's hard to explain .
Well , try .
You know , Jake , om ...
War 's war . Things happen .
Things happen ? ( CHUCKLES ) What does that mean ?
I thought we were going to do something , Frank .
There 's nothing to do , Jake .
( SOFTLY ) Who 's been talking to you ?
What 's going on , Frank ?
Okay .
I 'll call the other guys .
They 're not interested , Jake .
- What do you mean they 're not interested ? - They 're not interested .
We all talked about this . We 're all suffering the same symptoms , man .
( CHUCKLING ) Listen , the Army 's hiding something from us .
We got to find out what it is .
Jake , man , I got to go .
No , no , no , wait . Hold on . No , wait . Don 't hang up .
Jake , don 't call back anymore , okay ?
Wait ! I can 't do this by myself .
Frank ?
( PEOPLE CHATTERING )
We 'll get them . We 'll get them this afternoon . Have a good lunch .
Geary . Mr. Geary .
GEARY : Excuse me .
Who 's been talking to you , huh ? The Army ? Have they been talking to you ?
Nobody 's talking to nobody , all right . You don 't have a case .
All right ? Hey , hey . Keep your hands off me . Leave me alone .
Listen to me , you can 't do this .
You can 't walk away like this . We need your help .
- Jake , you need a doctor . - I don 't need a doctor .
The Army did something to me . I got to prove it . You got to help me .
There 's nothing I can do , all right ? Just leave me alone .
Something 's going on . You 're not telling me something .
What 's wrong with you ?
I 'll tell you what 's wrong with me . I don 't know you from Adam , right ?
You walk into my office with some bizarre-o story and demand that I check it out .
All right , fine . I did .
Now , I don 't know what kind of a fool you take me for ,
but you 've used and abused me , sir . I don 't like it .
Used you ?
That 's right . I checked with the Army 's bureau of information ,
- you never even went to Vietnam . - What 's that supposed to mean ?
It means that you and your friends are wacko !
You were all discharged on psychological grounds
- after some war games in Thailand . - War games in Thailand ?
Don 't you see what they 're doing ? That 's a lie .
We were in Da Nang , for God 's sake . You got to believe me .
Go fuck yourself , Singer . Hey ! Hey ! Gosh !
Hey ! Hey ! ( GRUNTING )
( SCREAMS )
What is this ? What is this ? Help ! Help !
( JACOB GRUNTING )
Come on , get in there , you cocksucker .
Get off of me !
( CAR ENGINE STARTING )
( GRUNTING )
Get the fuck off !
( BABY CRYING )
( GROANS )
You little fuck !
Mr. Singer . What an appropriate name for a man who can 't keep his mouth shut .
Who are you ? What do you want ?
( TIRES SCREECHING )
we 've been watching you for a long time , you and your friends .
Frightening people with foolish talk about the Army and experiments .
You 're in over your head , Mr. Singer . Men drown that way .
The Army was part of another life . Let it lie .
I hope we 've made our point , Mr. Singer .
( BOTH GRUNTING )
Kill this motherfucker !
( GRUNTING CONTINUES )
( JACOB SHOUTING )
( TIRES SCREECHING )
Help ! Help !
Fucking cocksucker ! Fuck ... Oh ! God damn it !
- Get out of here ! - Fucking ...
( BELL TINKLING )
Please give a little something to help the poor families .
( GASPING )
( WHIMPERING )
You poor , poor man .
H0 , ho , ho ! Merry , merry Christmas !
COP : This guy 's really hurt . You better get something in him .
Hi , I 'm Dr. Stewart . Can you tell me what happened ?
My back . I ... Ican 't move .
( BREATHING HEAVILY ) Get my Chiropractor .
Your back ? Did you fall ?
COP : He said he slipped on the pavement . He may have hit his head .
DR. STEWART : Does he have any identification ?
No wallet , nothing .
He stole it .
- Who did ? - Santa Claus .
I got to get the bastard .
It had my son 's picture in it . Gabe 's picture . It 's the only one I had .
DR. STEWART : You better get an orthopedic man in here . Is Dr. Davis on call ?
I 'll page him .
( GRUNTING )
Call my chiropractor .
We 're doing everything we can .
Louis Denardo , Nostrand Avenue .
I 'm going to have to move you a little bit , just to check for injuries .
- No , Doctor . - This may hurt a little .
No , no ... ( YELLING )
( CHUCKLING ) I don 't have to ask if you could feel that .
Oh , God damn it . I need Louis .
Who 's Louis ?
He 's out of it . Let 's take him down to X-ray .
( CLATTERING )
Gabe ?
( MAN 1 SPLUTTERING )
( MAN 2 MUMBLING )
( PEOPLE CHATTERING )
( PEOPLE GRUNTING )
( BLOWS )
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
Jezzie ...
Get me out of here .
- Where do you want to go ? - Home .
Home ? This is your home . You 're dead .
Dead ? ( LAUGHS ) No . No , I just hurt my back . I 'm not dead .
- What are you , then ? - I 'm alive !
- Then what are you doing here ? - ( CRYING ) I don 't know .
This isn 't happening .
What is happening ?
Get me out of here .
There is no out of here . You 've been killed . Don 't you remember ?
( JACOB PANTING )
( GASPING )
( SCREAMING )
( MEN CHATTERING )
- MAN 1 : Careful . - MAN 2 : Shit .
MAN 3 : Now , move it , guys . We 're losing him !
- MAN 1 : Watch it ! Careful . - MAN 2 : Yeah , shit .
MAN 3 : Move it for fuck 's sake .
He 's still pretty doped up .
I don 't think he 'll be able to talk yet , and I doubt he 'll recognize you .
- I just want to see him . - I 'll be outside if you need me .
Dad ? Hi .
It 's us .
You Okay ?
Jake , it 's me .
We heard what happened .
I ... I 'm not dead .
What ?
I 'm alive .
I 'm not dead .
Oh ! Oh , no . Of course you 're not .
You just hurt your back , that 's all . It 'll be fine . It just takes some time .
A month , they said .
( LAUGHING ) Just hang in there , Dad .
SARAH : Stop it . That is not funny .
( SCOFFS ) God .
What a mess , huh ?
( CLICKING TONGUE ) Oh , Jacob .
I still love you .
For whatever it 's worth .
MAN : Dream on .
( GASPING ) Oh , God , no !
What ? What ?
( JACOB SOBBING )
What ?
Oh , dear , what ? Tell me , what can I do ?
Help me .
Oh , no .
( NURSE CHATTERING )
- Jacob ? - NURSE : Shh .
- Jacob Singer ! - ( SHUSHING )
Jacob !
Sir , you 're going to have to keep your voice down .
( SHOUTING ) Where 's Jacob Singer ?
JACOB : Louis , I 'm in here !
Jake ? Where are you , Jake ?
- You can 't go in there . - Sir , can I help you , sir ?
Jacob ! Good God , Jake , what have they done ?
- Can I help you , sir ? - You can 't go in there .
- What is this , the Middle Ages ? - Don 't touch him !
And they call this modern medicine ? This is barbaric . Barbaric !
All right , just calm down .
Why don 't you just burn him at the stake and put him out of his misery ?
- Sir , you 're going to have to leave . - Stay back ! Don 't come near me !
- Do you understand ? - Call security .
Stay back !
Take one step and I 'll wrap this around your neck . Come on !
- All right , calm down . - I 'll call security .
- Back ! Back ! - Calm down .
Come on , Jake . Come on .
You can 't do that .
All right , make sure ...
- Now , sir , you can 't do this ! - Out of the way !
LOUIS : I 'm upset . I 'm really upset .
- ( LAUGHING ) That 's a crazy man . - Okay , they 'll nail him at the door downstairs .
( NURSES CHATTERING )
LOUIS : Watch your toes , Jake .
Well , you 've done it to yourself this time , haven 't you ?
Am I dying , Louis ?
( CHUCKLING ) From a slipped disk ?
That 'd be a first .
I was in hell .
I don 't want to die , Louis .
Well , I 'll see what I can do about it .
It 's all pain .
Straighten out your head .
Relax .
( JACOB GASPING )
- You ever read Meister Eckhart ? - No .
How did you get your doctorate without reading Eckhart ? Relax .
- ( LOUIS GRUNTING ) - ( BONES CRACKING )
- ( JACOB SIGHING ) - Okay , good . Now turn over gently .
Right side .
The other right , okay ?
You 're a regular basket case , you know that ?
Eckhart saw hell , too .
You know what he said ?
He said the only thing that burns in hell
is the part of you that won 't let go of your life .
Your memories , your attachments .
They burn them all away . But they 're not punishing you , he said .
They 're freeing your soul . Relax .
( GRUNTS )
Good .
So , the way he sees it ,
if you 're frightened of dying and you 're holding on ,
you 'll see devils tearing your life away .
But if you 've made your peace ,
then the devils are really angels freeing you from the Earth .
It 's just a matter of how you look at it , that 's all .
So don 't worry , okay ?
Okay ?
( LAUGHS )
Good . Relax . Relax .
Relax and wiggle your toes .
Come on , wiggle your toes .
( LOUIS EXHALING FORCEFULLY )
Perfect . We got it .
We got it .
Get on your back . Come on .
Easy . Okay ?
Now , let 's just give it a little try . I want to see if you can stand .
By myself ?
You can do it .
Come on .
Just give it a try , Jacob . Come on .
Attaboy . Go ahead .
Go ahead .
( CHUCKUNG )
Hallelujah .
( INAUDIBLE )
( TIRES SCREECHING )
- ( SCREECHING ) - ( JACOB GASPING )
( SOBBING )
Jake ?
What 's wrong ? It 's me .
Are you okay ?
Jesus Christ , where have you been ? I 've been worried sick .
I mean , it 's two days , and you don 't call me ?
I was in the hospital .
Oh , Jesus . In the hospital ?
Jake , honey , what hospital ? I called every hospital in the city .
( PHONE RINGING )
No , dont .
What 's going on ?
I 'm not here . You haven 't seen me .
- Hello ? - MAN : Is Jacob Singer there , please ?
- No . I haven 't seen him all night . - When do you expect him ?
Um , I don 't know .
Could you please tell him something for me ? Could you tell him that I was in Vietnam in ...
- Vietnam ? - That there was a secret experiment ...
- What experiment ? - L need to see him as soon as possible ...
- Hello . This is Jacob Singer . - Jacob , I was in country in ' 68 .
I was part of a chemical Warfare unit out of Saigon .
We conducted secret experiments for the government .
MV God !
- I need to see you . Are you there ? - Yeah .
- Do you want to know more ? - Yeah . Where can I meet you ?
Meet at the corner of 128th at West Side Highway in front of a coffee truck .
- Okay . How will I know you ? - You already know me , Jacob .
- I do ? - Yes ,
Just listen , make sure you 're not followed , okay ?
- All right . - Bye .
I knew it .
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Who was that ?
A chemist .
Part of a chemical warfare unit out of Saigon .
- I knew something was going on . - Jake , please don 't go .
Oh , I 'm sorry .
Jacob ?
Hi , I 'm Michael Newman .
Yeah .
I told you you 'd know me . I 've been tracking you for a long time .
I just wish I would have spoken to you before tonight .
Why are you following me ?
You 're one of the survivors , Jacob .
Come on . We can 't talk here . It 's not safe . Come on .
MICHAEL : ( SIGHING ) So , first I 'm arrested , right ?
Best LSD I ever made right down the drain .
I figured , " This is it , man . 20 years in the can if I 'm lucky . "
That was 1968 .
JACOB : Long time ago .
MICHAEL : Really . Next thing I know , I 'm on Rikers Island .
You ever been there , man ?
Well , suddenly , they take me from my cell , okay ?
They throw me in a waiting room with like , you know , bank teller windows .
Four Army colonels with medals up their asses
are standing on the other side .
They say to me , if I come to Vietnam for two years ,
no action , mind you , just work in a lab ,
they 'll drop all the charges and wipe the record clean .
But I 'd only been in jail for , like , 13 hours already .
Nam couldn 't be any worse .
Shows how little you knew .
Yeah , really . They had me by the balls . The next thing I know , I 'm in Saigon .
I 'm working in a top-secret lab synthesizing mind-altering drugs .
Not the street stuff .
They had us isolating special properties . The dark side , okay ?
They wanted a drug that increased aggressive tendencies .
They were scared , you know . They were worried .
They figured you guys were too soft , not fighting up to your potential .
They wanted something to stir you up , make you mad , you know ,
tap into your anger .
And we did it .
Most powerful thing I ever saw .
Even a bad trip , and believe me , I 've had my share ,
did not compare to the fury of the Ladder .
JACOB : The Ladder ?
Yeah . That 's what they called it .
A fast trip , straight down the ladder .
Right to the primal fear , right to the base anger .
I 'm telling you , man , it was powerful .
I know , I don 't need to tell you . You already know .
We did experiments on jungle monkeys . It worked .
They bashed each other 's heads in , gouged out their eyes , chewed off their tails .
The brass loved it .
Then they made us try it on Charlie .
We , uh ...
Took these POWs , you know ?
Just kids , really .
And we put them in this Courtyard ,
( CRYING ) and we fed them huge doses of the stuff , man .
I mean , they were worse than the monkeys , you know ?
I didn 't know men could do those things .
Anyway , there was ... There was this big offensive coming up , right ?
Everyone knew it .
Time magazine , Huntley-Brinkley .
And the brass were scared , man , because they knew we couldn 't win .
Morale was down , it was getting ugly in the States .
- Hell , you remember . - Yeah .
So , a couple days later , they decide to use the Ladder
on one test battalion .
Yours .
Just an infinitesimal dose in the food supply , they said ,
just to prove its effectiveness in the field .
They were sure your unit would have the highest kill ratio
of any in the whole goddamn offensive , and they were right , you did .
Except not the way they thought .
No one can remember that night .
I get flashes , but they don 't make sense .
What happened ?
Was there an offensive ?
Yeah , a couple days later . It was fierce .
But you guys never saw it .
But there was an attack ? It was a fight , right ?
Yeah , but not with the Cong .
With who ?
You killed each other .
What ?
It was brother against brother . No discrimination .
You tore each other to pieces .
My God .
I knew it would happen .
I warned them . I fucking warned them !
Oh , fuck .
( INAUDIBLE )
Who was I ? I was just some hippie chemist , right ?
What did I know ?
Fuck .
I talked to the guys who bagged the bodies .
They were in worse shape than you , believe me .
They saw what was left .
I needed to find you , you know ?
I felt responsible .
The Ladder was my baby .
( SIGHING )
I 'm going to Brooklyn .
Not with me , you 're not . I get lost in Brooklyn .
I know the way . Listen ...
This is all the money I have . Take me home , please .
Where 's your home ?
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
Dr. Singer !
( LAUGHS ) Well , it 's been a long time .
Hello , Sam .
Are you all right ?
Yeah , I 'm okay .
Do you want some help ? I can call upstairs .
No , no . That 's okay .
Thanks , Sam .
( SIGHS )
Sarah ?
( THUNDER CRACKLING )
( RAIN PATTERING )
Jed ? Eli ?
LOUIS : If you 're frightened of dying and you 're holding on ,
you 'll see devils tearing your life away .
If you 've made your peace ,
then the devils are really angels freeing you from the Earth .
( HEART BEATING )
( INAUDIBLE )
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
( LU LLABY TINKLING )
( MUSIC STOPS )
Gabe ?
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
Hi , Dad .
( WHISPERING ) It 's okay .
Come on . Let 's go up .
Come on .
He 's gone .
( SIGHS )
DOCTOR 1 : He looks kind of peaceful , the guy .
Put up a hell of a fight , though .
DOCTOR 2 : What 's the guy 's name ?
Singer . Jacob Singer .